Bruno P. Kinoshita

1 Courthouse Lane - Auckland 1010 - New Zealand (UTC+12)

I have 18 years of experience in telecommunications, banking, credit, retail, insurance, research, government, civil construction, and start-ups. Having had a wide variety of roles including backend developer, quality engineer, devops, architect, full stack, big data engineer, research software engineer, and frontend developer.

My main interests are NLP, Semantic Web, GIS, Workflow Management Systems, Data Journalism, and **Open Source** (including Community Management and Developer Relations). I am fluent in English and Portuguese. I have an intermediate level of Spanish and of Japanese, and basic of French and Te Reo Māori.

I value the **impact of the project** (e.g. work on climate change, accessibility, inclusion, open data, disease control, education, research, etc.) over technology and salary. I am a New Zealand tax resident, able to work in person in New Zealand, Australia, and Latin America — otherwise visa sponsorship is required.

Skills

Languages	Java, Python, JavaScript, PHP, R, C/C++, CSS, HTML, TypeScript, Shell, Perl, SQL
Frameworks	Spring Boot, Tornado, asyncio, Symfony, Vue.js
Systems	Linux, AWS, Docker, Singularity, OSX, Windows
Other	Open Source, NLP, GIS, Semantic Web, Linked Data, Community Management

Achievements

o Outreachy Mentor, CZI Grant, wdl-cwl-translator	2022
o Google Summer of Code (GSoC) Mentor, Jenkins Machine Learning Plug-in	2020
o Invited to become an Apache Software Foundation Member	2018
o Spirit of GovHack for amazing team work	2016
o NIWA Proactive Communicator	2016
o Organized two Jenkins meetups in Sao Paulo, Brazil as local community manager	2012 – 2013

Education

o Diploma in Business Administration, Mackenzie University	2008 - 2009
o BSc Information Systems, Mackenzie University	2003 - 2007

Training

o Machine learning in Python with scikit-learn. INRIA. Online (France Université Numérique MOOC)	. 2022
o $Vue\ 3+Typescript$. Vue Mastery. Online.	2021
o Data Science Math Skills. Duke University. Online (Coursera).	2020
o Building Web Applications in R with Shiny. DataCamp. Online.	2018
o OWASP NZ Day Advanced Web Hacking and Secure Coding. University of Auckland. New Zealand	. 2017
o AWS Concepts. Linux Academy. Online.	2016
o Linux Foundation Certified Systems Engineer. Linux Academy. Online.	2015
o Statistics and R for the Life Sciences. edX. Online.	2015
o Web Development with Servlets and JSP. Sun Microsystems. Sao Paulo, Brazil.	2007
o Microsoft Certified Solutions Associate career. Brás e Figueiredo. Sao Paulo, Brazil.	2003

Experience

o **Software Engineer**, Curii (Remote NZ, Europe, and USA teams)

Dec 2021 – actual

- CZI grant to contribute to CWL, CWL Viewer, cwltool, documentation, and community engagement.

o Research Software Engineer, NIWA (Remote NZ and UK teams)

Oct 2018 - Oct 2021

Cylc development, an Open Source workflow manager using JupyterHub, GraphQL, Python, Vue.js.

o Java Engineer, NIWA

Jun 2017 - Sep 2018

Java JEE development on EcoConnect web services, used by Fire Services NZ, Māori TV, DOC-NZ.

o Full Stack Software Developer, Spark Ventures

Oct 2016 - Jun 2017

- **AWS** development, build systems, and Java development using **SpringBoot**.

Software Developer / Operations, N/WA

Apr 2015 - Sep 2016

- Configuration management with Puppet and Ansible, automation, Java. Jenkins Cl.

o Senior Big Data Engineer, Boa Vista Servicos (Equifax)

Jun 2014 - Mar 2015

- Impala, HDFS, Hadoop. Cobol, Java. Development of the company first Big Data business cases.

o Senior Software Architect, Tokio Marine

Jan 2013 - May 2014

ActiveMQ cluster, internal workshops and trainings, web services, SSO, new Portal with Liferay.
Company-wide KPI monitoring implementation.

o Senior Infrastructure Engineer, Tokio Marine

Oct 2012 - Dec 2013

- Automation with **Jenkins** and **Puppet**.

o Senior Software Engineer, Tokio Marine

Oct 2011 - Sep 2012

- Java development with Servlets, Portlets, and LifeRay modules. SSO with OpenAM. Jenkins Cl.

o Senior System Analyst, Lojas Riachuelo

Jul 2011 - Sep 2011

- Java Swing development for retail POS system.

o Senior Software Quality Engineer, Vivo (Telefonica)

Jan 2010 - Jun 2011

- CRM development with Java and GWT. CI with Hudson, Sonar, Testlink, FishEye, and JIRA.

o Senior Software Engineer, Nossa Caixa Bank

Apr 2008 – Dec 2009

- .NET C# and Java support. Mainframes integration with Cobol, MQSeries, DirectConnect, Uniface.

o Junior System Analyst, Claro

Jun 2007 - Mar 2008

- Java web development and J2EE using Servlets, EJBs, JMS.

o Junior System Technician, Claro

Jan 2006 - May 2007

Java Swing and J2EE development on the VAS middleware platform.

o Value Added Services intern, Claro

Jul 2004 - Dec 2005

VAS middleware platform support, partner onboarding, marketing campaigns, billing integration.